A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Religious Interests, Series N FA323
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Riverside Church
  - Riverside Church - Building Committee - Women's Committee, 1927-1933 (Box 82, Folder 662)
    Women's Group granted permission to select one architect for Women's Floor of the Church; approval of work by the Building Committee. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Duncan Dandler (architect), H. C. Pelton.
  - Riverside Church - Building Committee - Letters of Appreciation, 1931-1933 (Box 83, Folder 663)
    List of people and firms who did work on the Church; letters of appreciation, acknowledgements. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    230.3A
  - Riverside Church - Newspaper Articles, Printed Statements, 1925-1929 (Box 83, Folder 664)
    Newspaper clippings, printed letter to the congregation about building plans. Correspondents include E. C. Carder, W. M. Crane, E. E. Sanborn, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    230.5
  - Riverside Church - Printed Statements - February 11, 1927 Statement (Box 83, Folder 665)
    Letter to the congregation about the plans for the new Church.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Miscellaneous Letters, 1929-1961 (Box 83, Folder 666)
    Receipt of records of Board of Trustees sent by Van Ness, sending of same to Gossett; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's resignation from the Board; honorary trustee in 1960. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, W. R. Conklin, W. T. Gossett, R. J. McCracken.
    230.7
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - John D. Rockefeller 3rd - Miscellaneous Letters, 1960 (Box 83, Folder 666A)
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - General, 1944-1949 (Box 83, Folder 667)
    Approval of the new seal for the church; Endowment Funds; resignation of W. M. Crane as Vice President of the Board, his death; resignation of F. A. Cole, E. L. Ballard and John D. Rockefeller 3rd, efforts to locate replacements; invitations to dinner meetings; resolutions relating to use of income from certain endowment funds; election of Winthrop Aldrich as Honorary Trustee; suggestions for possible new members for the Board; routine administrative matters. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, E. L. Ballard, A. L. Scott, E. C. Carder, W. M. Crane, W. T. Gossett, W. R. Conklin, J. C. Colgate, G. J. Heidt, R. J. McCracken, T. R. St. John.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - General, 1948-1949 (Box 83, Folder 667A)
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - General, 1931-1944 (Box 83, Folder 668)
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - General, 1956-1960 (Box 83, Folder 669)
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - General, 1949-1955 (Box 83, Folder 670)
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Dinner for Messrs. Ballard and Scott, 1932 (Box 83, Folder 671)
    Recognition of Ballard's services on Board; honor to Scott on his election; invitations, memos. Correspondents include E. E. Sanborn, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. R. Conklin, H. P. Fish.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - November 1953 Dinner for Deacons and Trustees, 1951-1955 (Box 83, Folder 672)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., N. L. Tibbetts, Boards of Trustees and Deacons.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Dinner for John D. Rockefeller, Jr., February 6, 1931, 1931-1957 (Box 83, Folder 673)
    Letters of thanks for the dinner; speeches of Arthur E. Bestor, Dr. Fosdick, Mr. Colgate. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, H. E. Fosdick, A. E. Bestor, J. C. Colgatet.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Endowment Fund Committee, 1928-1940 (Box 84, Folder 674)
    Opinions of trustees in regard to the Endowment Fund; "Declaration of Trust Creating 'The Riverside Church Fund'." Correspondents include G. J. Heidt, W. T. Gossett, Winthrop Aldrich, T. R. St. John, E. L. Ballard, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Family Representation on Boards, 1958 (Box 84, Folder 675)
    Dana S. Creel memo to Laurance S. Rockefeller, policy questions. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    Open per Meg H., August 2004.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Gift to Temple Emmanu-el, 1930-1932 (Box 84, Folder 676)
    Appreciation for the use of the synagogue while the church was without a place to worship; gift for a memorial at the synagogue (gift refused). Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. H. Fosdick, Irving Lehman.
  - Riverside Church - Trustee Minutes, 1939-1960 (Box 84, Folder 677)
    Incomplete minutes of meetings, June 1939-December 1952. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. L. Scott, Charles C. Tillinghast, Jr.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Committees - Lists of Trustees, 1931-1942 (Box 84, Folder 678)
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Successor to Mr. Scott, 1945 (Box 84, Folder 679)
    Retirement of A. L. Scott as President of the Board of Trustees. Selection of Noel Dowling as replacement. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. L. Scott, N. Dowling.
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Committee on Support, 1937-1950 (Box 84, Folder 680)
    Report on money-raising techniques, selection of Miss Francis Atkinson as Committee Secretary. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., F. Atkinson, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    230.71
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Committee on Support, 1937 (Box 84, Folder 681)
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Special Commitete on Organization and Program, 1938-1942 (Box 84, Folder 682)
    Confidential report of the Committee (dated November 13, 1939) on the nature, objectives and problems of the church. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, W. R. Conklin.
    230.72
  - Riverside Church - Trustees - Special Committee on Organization and Program - 1938 Organization and Program Minutes, 1939-1940 (Box 84, Folder 683)
    Correspondents include E. H. Fosdick, M. H. Biehl, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Riverside Church - Annual Meetings, 1949-1954 (Box 84, Folder 684)
    230.73
  - Riverside Church - Annual Meetings, 1956 (Box 84, Folder 684A)
  - Riverside Church - Treasurer's Statements, 1905-1949 (Box 85, Folder 685)
    Report on Endowments and Reserves at Riverside Church. Detailed information concerning each fund, November 1938; financial reports, 1945-1949. Correspondents include G. J. Heidt, Board of Trustees.
    230.8
  - Riverside Church - Treasurer's Statements, 1938 (Box 85, Folder 686)
    Report on Endowments and Reserves at Riverside church. Detailed information concerning each fund, November 1938; financial reports, 1945-1949. Correspondents include G. J. Heidt, Board of Trustees.
  - Riverside Church - Investments - Finance Committee, 1942-1949 (Box 85, Folder 687)
    Market value of the securities held in the Laura Spelman Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller Funds, payment of legacy in the Colgate Estate, statement of real estate held by the Linley Holding Corporation, administration of the Endowment Funds, commitments for uninvested balances of these funds; suggestions for investment in securities yielding 4% return, confidential statement on the investment value of selected concerns, use of the income from the endowment funds. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. J. Heidt, W. R. Conklin, J. C. Colgate, Vanderbilt Webb, B. P. Turnbull, George K. Weeks.
    230.9
  - Riverside Church - Investments - Finance Committee - Riverside Church Fund - List of Securities, 1932-1942 (Box 85, Folder 688)
    Investment of the William Colgate Fund; summary of endowment and reserve funds, 1934-1942. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, G. J. Heidt, W. R. Conklin, J. Colgate.
  - Riverside Church - Finances - General, 1948-1960 (Box 85, Folder 689)
    Auditor's reports, review of investment accounts. Correspondents include G. J. Heidt, R. H. Mansfield, H. P. Fish, A. N. Hastings.
    230.91
  - Riverside Church, "Finances, general, 1848-1960 (charts)," "Analysis of major repairs fund, 1947-1967 (with projections)," 1932-1982 "prepared in 1957 by GWS. ", GRAPH (Quantity 1) (Drawer B 1, Folder 89)
  - Riverside Church - Finances - Audits, 1957-1961 (Box 85, Folder 690)
    Auditor's reports on church accounts, 1947-1953. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., R. H. Mansfield, Haskins and Sells.
    230.91A
  - Riverside Church - Finances - Audits, 1953-1956 (Box 85, Folder 691)
  - Riverside Church - Finances - Finance Committees, 1953-1959 (Box 85, Folder 692)
    230.91B
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Church Monthly, 1928, 1929, 1930, 1932 (Box 86, Folder 693)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Church Monthly, 1938, 1940, 1941 (Box 86, Folder 694)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Church Monthly, 1944 (Box 86, Folder 695)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Church Monthly, 1945, 1946, 1947 (Box 86, Folder 696)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Church Monthly - Extras, April 1943, April 1944, December 1930 (Box 86, Folder 697)
    Selected issues: December 1930 - Architecture and Symbolism April 1943 - The Hemisphere Mind for Peace, Nelson A. Rockefeller. April 1944 - Recollections and Reflections, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Park Avenue Baptist Church Bulletins (and Extras), June 10, 1923-June 23, 1929 (Box 86, Folder 698)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Church School Monthly, October 1925-February 1926 (Box 86, Folder 699)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Riverside Description, 1841-1941 (Box 86, Folder 700)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Flemish Stained Glass Windows, circa 1923 (Box 86, Folder 701)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Subscription Vouchers from Park Avenue Baptist Church (Box 86, Folder 702)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, 1910 (Box 86, Folder 703)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Park Avenue Baptist Church Description, 1922 (Box 86, Folder 704)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Riverside Church Description (Box 87, Folder 705)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Building the Tower - Sermon, 1920 (Box 87, Folder 706)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - List of Members - Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, 1901, 1906, 1910, 1912, 1921 (Box 87, Folder 707)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - List of Members - Park Avenue Baptist Church, May 15, 1926 (Box 87, Folder 708)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - History and Importation of Carillon, 1920-1926 (Box 87, Folder 709)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - K. Lefevere's Carillon Recitals, 1926 (Box 87, Folder 710)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Printed Statements of Dr. Fosdick's Call, 1925 (Box 87, Folder 711)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Dr. Fosdick's Letter of Acceptance (Box 87, Folder 712)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Fifth Avenue Church Yearbooks, 1916-1917 (Box 87, Folder 713)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Iconography of Riverside Church (Box 87, Folder 714)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Riverside Church, 1931 (Box 87, Folder 715)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Riverside Church, 1931 (Box 88, Folder 716)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - The Meaning of Service (Sermon) (Box 88, Folder 717)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Printed Sermons - 21 Sermons (Fosdick), 1928-1932 (Box 88, Folder 718)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Printed Sermons - 21 Sermons (Fosdick), 1927-1936 (Box 88, Folder 719)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Printed Sermons - 21 Sermons (Fosdick), 1931 (Box 88, Folder 720)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - 21 Sermons (Fosdick), 1936-1939 (Box 89, Folder 721)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - 21 Sermons (Fosdick), 1927-1929 (Box 89, Folder 722)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Portfolio of Pictures (Box 89, Folder 723)
  - Riverside Church - Printed Materials - Picture of Construction of Riverside Church Playground, June 12, 1935 (Box 89, Folder 724)
  - Riverside Church - Legal Size Material (Box 102, Folder 816)
  - Riverside Church - Legal Size Material (Box 102, Folder 817)
  - Riverside Church - Legal Size Material (Box 102, Folder 818)
  - Riverside Church - Legal Size Material (Box 102, Folder 819)
  - Riverside Church - Radio and Television - General (Box 103, Folder 820)
    Index # 230R
    Diagram of antenna triangulation from top of antenna to ground.
  - Riverside Church - Union Theological Seminary - 1930 Building Program (Box 103, Folder 821)
    Index # 230.1B
    Drawing of lots and costs, Claremont Avenue to Riverside Drive and West 122nd Street to West 120th Street, by William A. White and Sons, Real Estate, New York, April 2, 1930.
  - Riverside Church - Union Theological Seminary - Negotiations, 1936 (Box 103, Folder 822)
    Index # 230.1C
    Map of Block 1991, Section 7, New York County, showing restrictions imposed by agreement of March 19, 1931.
  - Riverside Church - Pelton, Allen and Collens - General, 2 copies (Box 103, Folder 825)
    Index # 230P
    Sketch of extension of Riverside Church, "Final," January 1937.
  - Riverside Church - New Church Property - Union Theological Seminary (Box 103, Folder 826)
    Index # 230.1
    Blueprint of Pipe Chamber, union Theological Seminary, February 4, 1927.
  - Riverside Church - Union Theological Seminary - 1930 Building Program - General (Box 103, Folder 827)
    Drawing of Union Theological Seminary and Lots, West 120th Street to West 122nd Street and Riverside Drive to Claremont Avenue.
  - Riverside Church - Union Theological Seminary - Negotiations, 1936 (Box 103, Folder 828)
    Dimensions, January 24, 1936.
- Salvation Army
  - Salvation Army - Miscellaneous Appeals, 1929-1961 (Box 89, Folder 725)
    John D. Rockefeller's contribution to Salvation Army at Daytona Beach, Florida; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s letters of congratulations on Diamond Jubilee and retirement of Commander Parker; appeals declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, Henry W. Taft, Evangeline Booth.
    101
    Open per KWR, September 2004.
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1949-1953 (Box 89, Folder 726)
    Certificate of Incorporation, Frederick T. Gates' report on investigation of Salvation Army; John D. Rockefeller's contribution through Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial; appeals declined. Pledge April 24, 1916. War Work in France; S. S. 'Empress of Ireland' disaster; John D. Rockefeller's contribution to aid surviving dependent relatives. Home Service Fund, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial's contributions; Commander Booth's thanks for interview with John D. Rockefeller. John D. Rockefeller's objection to internal organization of Salvation Army; liquidation of Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial; administration of trust with provisions for distribution of income. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s letter congratulating General Evangeline Booth; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's contributions. Correspondents include Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, E. Booth, Ballinger Booth, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., C. Vanderbilt, Willard S. Richardson, James G. Blaine, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    101N
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1950-1953 (Box 89, Folder 726A)
  - Salvation Army - New York - John D. Rockefeller 3rd's Contribution and Correspondence, 1933-1957 (Box 90, Folder 727)
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1954-1960 (Box 90, Folder 728)
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1954-1955 (Box 90, Folder 729)
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1930-1948 (Box 90, Folder 730)
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1946-1948 (Box 90, Folder 730A)
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1918-1929 (Box 90, Folder 731)
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1896-1918 (Box 90, Folder 732)
  - Salvation Army - New York - General, 1919-1936 (Box 90, Folder 733)
  - Salvation Army - New York - Tarrytown and Westchester, 1937-1961 (Box 90, Folder 734)
    John D. Rockefeller's and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions to barracks at Tarrytown, renewal of pledges; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s pledge to Fresh Air Camp; Christmas donations. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Robert W. Gumbel, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    101T
  - Salvation Army - New York - Tarrytown and Westchester, 1956-1958 (Box 90, Folder 735)
  - Salvation Army - Volunteers of America, 1947-1960 (Box 91, Folder 736)
    Requests for contribution. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Maud B. Booth.
    101.1
  - Salvation Army - Volunteers of America, 1929-1947 (Box 91, Folder 737)
- Seamen's Church Institute
  - Seamen's Church Institute - General, 1944-1959 (Box 91, Folder 738)
    John D. Rockefeller contributions through Rockefeller Foundation to community center for sailors' religious work. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gift of $250,000 for expansion of facilities. Contributions by Laurance S. Rockefeller. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Dana S. Creel.
    78
  - Seamen's Church Institute - General, 1924-1944 (Box 91, Folder 739)
  - Seamen's Church Institute - General, 1907-1915 (Box 91, Folder 740)
  - Seamen's Church Institute - American Seamen's Friend Society, 1908-1924 (Box 91, Folder 741)
    78.2
- Billy Sunday
  - Billy Sunday - General, 1917-1926 (Box 91, Folder 742)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s purchase of box seats at Carnegie Hall for William A. Sunday Evangelistic Campaign Choir Song Festival and Victory Concert; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s purchase of tickets. Acceptances and declinations of prayer meeting at John D. Rockefeller's home; subscriptions to Billy Sunday Campaign; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions. Mr. Richardson's report on Billy Sunday campaign in Baltimore, recommendations about conducting New York campaign. Womans Conservation Committee. Gifts to Billy Sunday, 1921-1957. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Robert W. Gumbel, W. B. Miller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
    108Su
    Open per KWR and Peter Johnson, September 15, 2004.
  - Billy Sunday - General, 1916-1917 (Box 91, Folder 743)
  - Billy Sunday - General, 1954-1957 (Box 91, Folder 744)
  - Billy Sunday - General, 1927-1954 (Box 92, Folder 745)
  - Billy Sunday - Gifts to Billy Sunday, 1921-1934 (Box 92, Folder 746)
  - Billy Sunday - Contributions, 1916-1923 (Box 92, Folder 747)
  - Billy Sunday - Campaign Lists, 1916-1917 (Box 92, Folder 748)
    See also Box 104, Folder 829
  - Billy Sunday - Printed Materials - Programs, 1917 (Box 92, Folder 749)
    Reports of campaign, newspaper clippings, biographical sketch of Billy Sunday.
  - Billy Sunday - Printed Materials - Newspapers, 1917 (Box 92, Folder 750)
    See also Box 103, Folder 823
  - Billy Sunday - Printed Materials - Newspapers, 1917 (Box 103, Folder 823)
    "Evangelistic Monthly - Tabernacle Echoes," Vol. 1, No. 8, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, July 1917. "New York Souvenir Edition."
  - Billy Sunday - Campaign Lists (Box 103, Folder 829)
    Table List, Hotel Savoy, New York, May 18, 1916.
- Young Men's Bible Class
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1903-1921 (Box 92, Folder 751)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1924-1926 (Box 92, Folder 752)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1920-1926 (Box 92, Folder 753)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1933-1943 (Box 93, Folder 754)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1924-1933 (Box 93, Folder 755)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1944-1957 (Box 93, Folder 756)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1949-1957 (Box 93, Folder 756A)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Annual Dinners, 1943-1944 (Box 93, Folder 757)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - V. L. Abbey Correspondence, 1909-1950 (Box 93, Folder 758)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - W. H. Atwood, 1909-1938 (Box 93, Folder 759)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - A. Leroy Chipman, 1928-1965 (Box 93, Folder 760)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - A. Leroy Chipman, 1921-1927 (Box 94, Folder 761)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - A. Leroy Chipman, 1906-1924 (Box 94, Folder 762)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (A - Cooke) (Box 94, Folder 763)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (Damon - Engberry) (Box 94, Folder 764)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (Firth - Geer) (Box 94, Folder 765)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (Hammill - Hodge) (Box 94, Folder 766)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (J-L) (Box 94, Folder 767)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (M) (Box 94, Folder 768)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (N - Sage) (Box 95, Folder 769)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (Sanders - Stevens) (Box 95, Folder 770)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (Tafel), 1909-1938 (Box 95, Folder 771)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (Tafel), 1903-1908 (Box 95, Folder 772)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Members (Tremp - Troxell) (Box 95, Folder 773)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Johnson W. Troxell, 1912-1931 (Box 95, Folder 774)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - W. S. Richardson, 1904-1934 (Box 95, Folder 775)
    Payment of salary, class leadership, personal relations with family. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Young Men's Bible Class - John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1905-1935 (Box 95, Folder 776)
    Resignation as class leader, pledge for class activities, honorary President, gift of Bible. Address at 50th Anniversary. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Materials for 50th Anniversary Dinner, 1907 (Box 95, Folder 777)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - John D. Rockefeller's Address of 1904, 1904-1911 (Box 95, Folder 778)
    Copies of "The Beginning of a Business Life." Given May 7, 1904.
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Membership, 1906-1925 (Box 96, Folder 779)
    Lists of members.
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Membership, 1909-1922 (Box 96, Folder 780)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Miscellaneous, 1948-1961 (Box 96, Folder 781)
    Letters of appreciation for addresses; arrangements for speakers. Billy Sunday campaign; aid to former members. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s addresses on "Love" and "Civilization and Religion." David Rockefeller's speech on Morningside Heights development; John D. Rockefeller 3rd's speech on Europe 1947, on Far East 1948, Japan 1953, Southern Asia 1953. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Ivy Lee, H. E. Fosdick, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Miscellaneous - David Rockefeller, 1948-1955 (Box 96, Folder 781A)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Miscellaneous - Directory (1958-1959, 1953-1954, 1953-1954, 1958-1959 (Box 96, Folder 782)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Miscellaneous - John D. Rockefeller 3rd Address, 1946-1953 (Box 96, Folder 783)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Miscellaneous, 1931-1951 (Box 96, Folder 784)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Miscellaneous, 1901-1930 (Box 96, Folder 785)
    See also Box 103, Folder 824
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - Announcements (Postcards), circa 1901-1919 (Box 96, Folder 786)
    Announcements, directories, appeals, descriptions.
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - Announcements (Postcards), 1923-1928 (Box 97, Folder 787)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - Annual Dinner - Miscellaneous, 1897-1922 (Box 97, Folder 788)
  - Young Men's Bible Class - Printed Materials - The Church Monthly, February 1927, April 1944 (Box 97, Folder 789)